Welcome back. In this video, we're going to talk about converting nondeterministic
欢迎回来。在这段视频中，我们将讨论如何将不确定性
finite automata into deterministic finite automata. Here again is our little diagram
将有限自动机转化为确定性有限自动机。这又是我们的小图表
of the pipeline of a lexical analyzer, how one is constructed. So beginning with the
词法分析器的流水线是如何构造的。所以从
lexical specification, we write our regular expressions. Last time we talked
词法规范，我们编写正则表达式。上次我们谈话的时候
about the step, the conversion of regular expressions and the non-deterministic
关于步骤、正则表达式的转换和不确定性
finite automata and this time we're going to talk about this step. And as you might
有限自动机，这一次我们要讨论这一步。就像你可能会做的那样
guess in the final video in the series we'll talk about the final step which is
我猜在本系列的最后一段视频中，我们将讨论最后一步，即
the implementation of DFA's. So here's the Nondeterministic Finite Automata and we
DFA的实现。所以这里是非确定性有限自动机，我们
finished up with last time. And, the first thing we're gonna discuss today is an
最后一次结束了。今天我们要讨论的第一件事是
important idea called the Epsilon Closure of a state. And the basic idea of the
一个重要的概念叫做国家的爱普西隆闭合。它的基本思想是
epsilon culture is that I pick the states. And it could a set of states but we'll
爱普西隆文化是我挑选各州。它可以是一组州，但是我们会
just do it for a single state. And then I look at all the states that I can reach by
只为一个州这么做就行了。然后我看看我能到达的所有州
following only epsilon moves. And so b is the state that we're starting with so b
只跟随ε运动。所以b是我们开始的状态，所以
would be included in the set and then there's an epsilon move to c. So c would
会包括在集合中，然后会有ε移动到c，所以c会
be included in the set and there's another epsilon move to d so d would be included
被包括在集合中，并且有另一个ε移动到d，所以d将被包括在内
in the set. So we would say, the epsilon closure of b is = the set b c d. And let's
在片场。所以我们会说，b的ε闭包是，集合b，c，d，让我们
do one more as an example. Want to take the epsilon closure of g. And when we
再做一个例子。我想用g的ε闭包。当我们
switch colors up to this one, I'll erase that and to this one in pink, Our
把颜色换成这个，我会把它擦掉，换成粉红色的，我们的
purple-ish pink. So the epsilon closure of g, we always have to follow all the
略带紫色的粉红色。所以g的ε闭合，我们总是要遵循所有
epsilon transitions out of g. So, h would be in the epsilon closure of g but it's
ε从g跃迁出来，所以h会在g的ε闭包中，但它是
not just single epsilon move. This is recursive. So any number of epsilon moves
不只是单一的ε运动。这是递归的。所以任何数量的ε移动
that I can take, all of those states are included in the epsilon closure of g. So,
我能理解的是，所有这些态都包含在g的ε闭合中。所以，
in fact, i would also be included. A would be included and b and c and d will also be
事实上，我也会被包括在内。a将包括在内，b、c和d也将包括在内
included And now, if I look at all of these states that have been colored in the
包括在内，现在，如果我查看所有这些状态，这些状态都已经在
light purple color. I can see that I can't reach any new states from those states
浅紫色。我看得出来，我不能从那些州到达任何新的州
using only epsilon moves and so the epsilon closure of g would be equal to and
仅使用ε运动，因此g的ε闭合等于和
[inaudible] out here it's a, b, c, d. Ghi. Okay. So that is the epsilon closure of a
[听不见]外面是a，b，c，d，ghi。好吧。这就是一个
state. Recall from the last video that an NFA maybe in many states any given point
州政府。回想上一段视频，NFA可能在许多州的任何给定点
in time that is because of the choices it can make for a given input and NFA may
随着时间的推移，这是因为它可以为给定的输入做出选择，并且NFA可以
reach multiple different states. And the question we want to address now is how
到达多个不同的州。我们现在要解决的问题是如何
many different states can it be in? Well if a non-deterministic automaton has n
它可以是很多不同的州吗？如果一个不确定的自动机有n个
states. And it winds up in some subset of those states as how big can that subset b
各州。它在这些州的一些子集中结束，比如子集b可以有多大
will clearly the cardinality of that said has to be less than or equal to n. So the
显然，所说的基数必须小于或等于n，所以
NFA can get into a most and different states. Now instead, I want to know the
NFA可以进入一种非常不同的状态。现在，我想知道
number of different subsets, well how many different subsets are there of any things.
不同子集的数量，任何事物有多少不同的子集。
Well that means there are two to the n - one possible subsets of n states. And
这意味着有n个态的2到n-1个可能的子集。和
there's something very interesting about this number. First of all it's a very big
这个数字有一些非常有趣的地方。首先它是一个非常大的
number so clearly the NFA can get into lots of different configurations
很明显，NFA可以有很多不同的配置
particularly one it has a lot of different states but the important thing is that
特别是它有很多不同的州，但重要的是
this is a finite set of possible configurations. And this is going to give
这是一组有限的可能配置。这将会给我们带来
us the seed of the idea. For converting an NFA into a DFA or Deterministic Automata
我们是这个想法的种子。用于将NFA转换为DFA或确定性自动机
because all we have to be able to do to convert a Nondeterministic Automata into
因为我们所能做的就是把一个不确定的自动机转化为
Deterministic Automata is come up with a way for the Deterministic Automata to
确定性自动机为确定性自动机的研究提供了一条新的途径
simulate for the [inaudible] of the Nondeterministic Automata and the fact
非确定性自动机的[听不见]和事实的模拟
that the Nondeterministic Automata can only get into a finite set of
非确定性自动机只能进入有限的
configurations even that configurations is very large, is exactly what we will
配置即使是非常大的配置，也正是我们要做的
exploit in the construction. Now we're ready to give the construction showing how
在建设中加以利用。现在我们准备好给出展示如何
to map an arbitrary nondeterministic finite automaton to an equivalent
将任意不确定有限自动机映射到等价的
deterministic finite automaton. So let's begin by saying what's in our NFA. So,
确定性有限自动机。所以让我们先说一下我们的NFA里有什么。所以,
we'll have a set of states, Which we'll call s and these are the states of the
我们将有一组状态，我们称之为s，这些是
Nondeterministic machine. There's a star t state, a little s which is one of the
不确定机器。这里有一个星t态，一个小的s，它是
states and there is a set of final states F. And then we also have to give the
有一组最终的状态F，然后我们还必须给出
transition function and I want to write out the state transition function. I want
转移函数，我想写出状态转移函数。我想要
to use the state transition function to define a, a operator that we're going to
要使用状态转移函数来定义一个运算符，我们将
find handy for defining our DFA. So I'd say that a applied to a set of states so x
发现可以方便地定义我们的DFA。所以我想说a适用于一组州，所以x
here is a set of states and a is a character in the input language. So, a and
下面是一组状态，a是输入语言中的字符。所以，a和
x is = those states y such that there is some x little x here, single state in the
x is=那些状态y，这里有一些x小x，在
set of states such that there's a transition from x to y on input a. Okay.
一组状态，在输入a上有一个从x到y的转变，好的。
So this is just a way of saying I've given the transition function at this set level.
所以这只是一种方式，我已经给出了这个集合水平的转移函数。
It says for a given set of state x, show me all the states that you can reach on
它说，对于给定的一组状态x，向我展示您可以到达的所有状态
input a. Alright. So now we're ready to define our DFA. So what will the DFA be?
输入a。好的。现在我们准备好定义我们的DFA了。那么DFA会是什么呢？
Well, it's gonna have to have all of these things. It's gonna have to have, perhaps
嗯，它必须拥有所有这些东西。它可能必须要有，也许
where the states are? What are the start state is? What's the final states are and
各州在哪里？开始状态是什么？最终的州是什么？
what's the transition function is? So let's begin with the set of states. The
转移函数是什么？那么让我们从一组状态开始。这个
states will be the subsets Of s. So the states of the DFA will be all possible
状态将是s的子集。因此，DFA的状态将是所有可能的
subsets of the states of the NFA so there will be one state of DFA for each subset
NFA状态的子集，因此每个子集将有一个DFA状态
of possible, each possible subset of states of the NFA. And of course this is
可能的是NFA的每个可能的状态子集。当然这是
potentially a very big number but it's still finite and so we can use that set
可能是一个非常大的数字，但它仍然是有限的，所以我们可以使用该集合
of, of subsets of states as the states based of the Deterministic machine So, now
作为基于确定性机器的状态的状态子集的So，Now
what's the start state of the DFA. Well that's going
DFA的起始状态是什么。嗯，那是要去的。
to
至
be the  epsilon closure. Now one of the set of final states, Well,
是epsilon的闭合。现在是一组最终状态中的一个，
so the final states will be consist of those state x and every member of the
所以最终状态将由这些状态x和
states of the DFA are sets of states of the NFA. So that x is a set and is can be
DFA的状态是NFA的状态集合。因此x是一个集合，且可以
every x such that x intersected with the set of final states of the NFA is not
使得x与NFA的最终状态集相交的每个x不
empty. And finally we need to define the transition function. And do we do that?
空的。最后，我们需要定义转移函数。我们要这么做吗？
Well, we, we need to say that for a given state x and another state y, when is there
那么我们，我们需要说，对于一个给定的状态x和另一个状态y，什么时候
a transition between them on some input a. Well that, there will be such a transition
它们之间在某些输入上的转换。嗯，会有这样的转换
under that conditions and well let's write them out. So, remember we're in state x.
在这种情况下，我们把它们写出来。所以，记住我们是在x州。
And what do we need to know? Well we need to know, the set of states that we can
我们需要知道什么？我们需要知道，我们可以
reach on input A, and we'll be justifying that that's A of X, and then once we've
到达输入A，我们将证明这是X的A，然后一旦我们
gotten to where these, once we've seen where we can go from the set of states X
到达这些的地方，一旦我们看到我们可以从状态集合X到哪里
of input A. There's also a possibility of making [inaudible] after that so
输入A也有可能在那之后变得[听不见]，所以
furthermore we have to take the [inaudible] closer of that set of states,
此外，我们必须将这组状态中的(听不见的)更近一些，
okay? And So we'll say that there's a transition from x to y if y is equal to
好吧?所以我们说，如果y等于，就会有一个从x到y的转变
this set of states. Alright, And notice that there's only one such set of states
这组州。好的，注意只有一组这样的州
for any x and that guarantees of this is a deterministic machine. Each machine, each
对于任何x，这是一台确定性机器。每台机器，每台
state will only have one possible move on each input so. We can just, now it goes to
状态将在每个输入上只有一次可能的移动。我们可以，现在它去了
our check list and see if we have a deterministic machine. We have a finite
我们的核对表，看看我们是否有一台确定性的机器。我们有一个有限的
set of states. We have a start state and we have a set of final states and we have
一组州。我们有一个开始状态，我们有一组最终状态，我们有
a transition function with only one more per input and no epsilon moves. And so
每个输入只有一个以上且没有ε移动的转移函数。因此，
that is in fact a deterministic machine and the property that it maintain is that
这实际上是一台确定性机器，它维护的属性是
each step of computation. The state of the DFA records the set of possible states
计算的每一步。DFA的状态记录一组可能的状态
that the NFA could have gotten into the same input So let's work to an example of
NFA可以进入相同的输入，所以让我们来举一个例子
constructing a Deterministic machine from a Nondeterministic machine. Here's the
从不确定的机器构造确定的机器。这是
Nondeterministic Finite Automata that we built in the last video and again this is
我们在上一个视频中构建的非确定性有限自动机，同样，这是
the one that I used at the beginning of the video to define epsilon enclosure. So
我在视频开头用来定义epsilon外壳的那个。所以
we're gonna do the example slightly differently than the construction I gave
我们要做的示例与我给出的结构略有不同
on the previous slide. If we actually have to write out all the subsets of this many
在上一张幻灯片上。如果我们真的要写出这许多东西中的所有子集
states, it will take us a very, very long time. And it turns out that not all of the
在美国，这将花费我们非常、非常长的时间。事实证明，并不是所有的
subsets were actually used by the DFA. So we're just going to enumerate the states
子集实际上由DFA使用。所以我们只需列举各州
that we actually need and we'll do that by beginning with the start sta te of DFA and
这是我们真正需要的，我们将从DFA的开始阶段开始
then working out which additional states are required. So how do we do that? Well,
然后计算出需要哪些额外的状态。那么我们该怎么做呢？井,
we begin with the start state of the NFA which is just this state a. And then
我们从NFA的开始状态开始，也就是这个状态a。然后
recall at the start of the DFA is the epsilon closure of that state so that
回想一下，在DFA开始时是该状态的epsilon闭合，因此
corresponds to this purple set here. Alright. So the first state of the DFA,
与这套紫色相对应。好的。所以DFA的第一个状态，
the start state is the subset of states a, b, c, d, h, i. And now we have to work out
开始状态是状态a，b，c，d，h，i的子集，现在我们必须计算出
from this particular state from the start state what happens on each of the
从这个特定状态(从开始状态开始)，在每个
impossible input values. So, the alphabet of this machine is one and zero so you
不可能的输入值。所以，这台机器的字母表是1和0，所以你可以
would have to have two transitions out of the state, one for an input of one and one
必须有两次状态转换，一次是输入一次，另一次是输入一次
for an input of zero. So let's do input zero first. And, we can see looking at the
输入为零。那么让我们先输入0。而且，我们可以看到，看着
purple set that there's only one possible transition and that's from the state D to
紫色设置，只有一种可能的转换，那就是从状态D到
the state F. So certainly the state s is included in the set of states if the NFA
因此，如果NFA将状态s包括在状态集合中，那么可以肯定的是，状态s包括在状态集合中
can reach but then once we get the state f there's a lot of epsilon moves that we can
可以达到，但是一旦我们达到这个状态，就会有很多ε运动，我们可以
take and so in fact the second state of the DFA corresponds to a much larger set.
实际上，DFA的第二个状态对应于一个大得多的集合。
It's all the, it's the epsilon closure of f and that is, this set of states f, g, h,
这都是，这是f的ε闭包，也就是这组状态f，g，h，
i, a, b, c, and d, okay. So these are the set of possible states that the NFA could
i，a，b，c和d，好的。因此，这些是NFA可能会出现的一组状态
be in after reading a single zero. Next, let's consider what happens from the start
只读了一个零就进去了。接下来，让我们考虑一下从一开始会发生什么
state on an input of one. Which possible states can the NFA reach? And, if we look
输入为1时的状态。NFA可以达到哪些可能的州？而且，如果我们看一下
at the transition function, we see there are two possible moves that the NFA could
在转换函数中，我们看到NFA可以采取两种可能的举措
take. It could be in state c. In which case it would move to state e or it could
拿走。它可以处于状态c。在这种情况下，它将移动到状态e，或者它可以
have been state i, that's also part of the purple set in which case it would move to
状态I，这也是紫色集合的一部分，在这种情况下，它会移动到
state j. So, there are two possible states that the NFA can get into as a result of
状态j。因此，NFA可以进入两种可能的状态，其结果是
reading a one and then after that, there's a bunch of epsilon moves that can take
读完1之后，会有一系列的ε动作
place and in fact, it turns out that after reading a one, the machine could be in any
实际上，在读完1之后，机器可能在任何
state except for state f. And that's this set of states and you'll notice that this
除了f之外的州。这就是这组州，你会注意到这
particular set of states, the read set includes the final state of the NFA so
特定状态集合，读集合包括NFA So的最终状态
this is also a final state indicating that after reading one, the NFA could be in an
这也是一个最终状态，表明在读取1之后，NFA可能处于
accepting state. So this would be an accepting state of the DFA Well, we still
接受状态。因此，这将是DFA的一种接受状态。那么，我们仍然
have to fill in for both of the two states that we've added here. The two states on
必须填写我们在这里添加的两个州。上的两个州
the right of the machine what they do on input zero, what they do on input one. So
机器的右边是他们在输入0上做什么，他们在输入1上做什么。所以
let's figure that out. So beginning with the red state on input zero, what can
让我们弄清楚这一点。那么从输入0上的红色状态开始，什么可以
happen? Well, look the red state includes state d and it can move to state f but
发生了什么？好，看，红色状态包括状态d，它可以移动到状态f，但是
we've already computed what happens on the epsilon, what the epsilon closure that is
我们已经计算了epsilon上会发生什么，epsilon闭合是什么
just the green state. And so if I'm in the red state and I read zero, I move to the
只有绿州。因此，如果我处于红色状态，并且读数为0，我将移动到
green state. If I'm in the red state and I read a one, you'll see that both states,
绿州。如果我在红色的州，我读到1，你会看到这两个州，
NFA states c and i are in the red set. And so, it just takes us back to the red set.
国家足协规定c和i在红色组。所以，它把我们带回了红色的场景。
And similarly for the green state, if I read a one, I move to the red state. And
同样，对于绿色状态，如果我读到1，我就会转到红色状态。和
if I read a zero, I stay in the green state. And so, this then is our
如果我读到零，我就会保持在绿色状态。所以，这就是我们的
deterministic machine down here. This is the deterministic machine and again, it
这里有一台确定性机器。这是一台确定性的机器，再一次，它
simulates the NFA. So every move at the deterministic machine, it records the set
模拟NFA。所以确定性机器的每一个动作，都会记录下
of possible states that the NFA could be in and it will accept a string infinitely
NFA可能所处的可能状态，并且它将无限接受字符串
if the NFA could accept the string.
如果NFA可以接受该字符串。